Bill Trikalinos

Panagi Tsaldari 16, 15127, Melissia, Attica, Greece 0030 6949194977 billtrik@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with experience in web development and expertise in Javascript.

My experiences vary from creating web sites, reusable components and fully featured user interfaces, to being a system administrator as well as to design and implement complex architectures.

I really enjoy using the latest web technologies and always welcome the opportunity to learn something new.

SKILLS

Front-end: HTML(5), CSS(3), Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, SCSS, HAML, require.js **Back-end**: Ruby On Rails, Ruby, node.js, Laravel, PHP, MongoDB, MySQL, redis, bash

Other Languages: C, C++, Java (university level)

Methodologies: Scrum, TDD

Web Communications: XHR, JSONP, XDomain, REST APIs, WebSockets

Other: git, Unix, Phonegap, Photoshop

Javascript:

- · Cross-browser vanilla JS
- · Focus on Performance (loading, parsing, executing)
- (AMD, commonJS, UMD) Modules
- Templating, Promises, MVC
- Backbone.js, Angular.js, Ember.js, Handlebars.js, Grunt.js, Gulp.js, Bower.js
- Teaspoon, Karma.js, Mocha, Chai.js, Sinon.js, Zombie.js, CasperJS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Javascript Software Engineer

10/2011 - Onwards

skroutz.gr (Athens)

- **Skroutz analytics**: X-Domain tracking platform that tracks and reports data inside affiliated sites. Designed and implemented the Javascript client. Vanilla Javascript, X-Domain session tracking, X-Domain communications
- Rewrote the whole JS codebase using Coffescript, AMD modules and Require.js. Also created reusable components and plugins
- · Chrome extension that consumes the REST API of the site. Implemented the OAuth2 dance
- Inception, design and implementation of JS continuous integration testing platform, using Testswarm and Jenkins
- Library implementing sequential execution for async based tests
- jQuery plugins:
 - Selectorablium
 - Templating wizard
- Widgets and widget-loading library that implemented:
 - JSONP
 - o Cross-browser events handling

Software Engineer

02/2011 - 10/2011

Generation-y.gr (Athens)

- Created a number of web-sites from the .PSD up
- HTML, CSS, Javascript and Ruby On Rails development

Software Engineer / System Administrator

02/2010 - 01/2011

Mindradio.gr (Athens)

- Dedications: Web-app implementing a dedications system. Backend that provides playlist like auditing of submissions, integration with existing Icecast scheduling mechanism. Client that integrates with Facebook API and provides audio recording
- HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP development for the company sites and the admin interfaces
- Unix daemon creation that monitors changes in files and updates database accordingly
- Web-based File Manager

System Administrator

01/2005 - 06/2005

Support Department, Computer Science Department, University of Ioannina

- Maintenance and support
- · Accounts management
- System Administration (BSD, Solaris)

Software Engineer – Web Developer

2010 - Onwards

Freelancer

- Created a number of responsive web-sites using the Laravel PHP framework
 - o http://www.max-e-mize.co.uk
 - o http://www.petrinonaxos.gr
 - o http://www.evrofarma.gr
- Created an e-book reader phonegap application
- Created a custom ERP solution using PHP
- Personal project tracking web-app using the Ruby On Rails framework
- Chrome extension to provide sensible cinema filtering using ember.js

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS PROFILES

- github.com/skroutz/analytics.js
- github.com/skroutz/selectorablium
- github.com/billtrik/karma-fixture
- github.com/billtrik
- stackoverflow.com/users/659610/basiloungas
- linkedin.com/pub/bill-trikalinos/a/85b/1ba

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science, University of Ioannina

2013

Upper division Second-class honors (2:1)

Courses of interest:

- Web Development (Javascript, PHP, jsp-servlets, XML)
- Object Oriented Design Principles (Single Responsibility Principle (SRP), Liskov Substitution Principle (LSP), Low Coupling Principle (LCP), Dependency Inversion Principle (DIP), Open-Closed Principle (OCP), Interface Segregation Principle)
- Parallel Processing (MPI, OPENMP)
- Network Programming (BSD Sockets)
- Computer Systems Security (Buffer overflows, Man-in-the-middle attack)

LANGUAGES

- English Cambridge Proficiency degree
- Greek Native

INTERESTS

Gaming, Music, Cinema, CrossFit, Martial Arts, Travelling, Motorcycles

OTHER

Military obligations fulfilled (Hellenic Air Forces - Airman)

04/2013 - 12/2013